Victor Mandere Mose

+254707343204 || vicmose.vm@gmail.com || linkedin.com/in/victor-mose || github.com/vmose

SUMMARY

Analytics specialist trained in Management Consulting. 4 years experience with 20+ projects completed of varying degrees of complexity and scope in data-modelling, data-visualisation and machine-learning. Knowledgeable in operational frameworks related to data such as Python, SQL and BigQuery. Certified Mobile Developer and Business Intelligence enthusiast.

SKILLS

Programming: Python, SQL, Javascript, CSS, HTML, GraphQL

Software: PostgreSQL, MySQL, Audit Command Language (ACL), Flask, React.js, BigQuery, Git, Excel

Statistical Packages: SPSS, R

Dashboards/Visuals: Microsoft PowerBI, Looker Studio, Tableau, D3.js, Python (Matplotlib, Seaborn), Al/ML: Linear & Logistic regression, Decision Trees & Random Forest, SVM, PCA, NLP, Recommender

Systems, K-Means Clustering and K-Nearest Neighbour.

Languages: English (Fluent), Kiswahili (Native), French (Conversational)

WORK EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE Independent Consultant - Data Specialist

Remote/Nomad Nov 2022- Present

- Generated data cleaning and preprocessing scripts using Pandas and NumPy, reducing data cleaning time by 70%.
- Built and maintained 150+ interactive data visualisations and business intelligence dashboards using Tableau, Looker, D3.js, Plotly and PowerBI, providing real-time insights to stakeholders and executives.
- Designed and optimised SQL queries for complex data-analysis tasks, reducing query execution time by 50%.
- Developed and sustained automated data-processing pipelines using Bash shell scripts, reducing processing time by 50%.
- Constructed and implemented custom machine-learning algorithms using Python and TensorFlow, achieving up to 90% accuracy on classification tasks using cross-validation, grid search, and other techniques to optimise model performance.
- Conducted A/B tests using Google Optimize and Google Analytics to optimise website landing pages achieving an average statistical significance of over 85%, resulting in 20% increase in conversion rates.
- Engineered RESTful APIs using Flask that facilitated seamless integration with other systems and applications; improved efficiency and productivity by 25%
- Architected scalable application prototypes using AWS Elastic Beanstalk and EC2, ensuring high availability and fault tolerance with an average iteration time of 1.5 weeks.

GRANDE AFRIQUE CONSULTING

Data Analytics Consultant

Nairobi, Kenya Nov 2020- Nov 2022

- Applied statistical and predictive modelling techniques to build, maintain, and improve on multiple real-time decision systems with clients reporting a rise in efficiency of up to 40% in day-to-day operations.
- Queried with PostgreSQL, BigQuery, ACL and Arbutus to automate the data flow on routine tasks with each script having over 50 lines on average.
- Coded 100+ programs in Python using established repositories i.e. Pandas, NumPy, scikit-learn
- Visualised over 40 datasets with Python, Microsoft PowerBI and Tableau.
- Directed end-to-end delivery of Analytics Support projects for eight quarterly, ensuring timely completion, accuracy and high-quality delivery; retained 90%+ client satisfaction rate
- Created complete and effective Project Proposal documents for prospecting stakeholders using the industry standard 6-step process.

KENYA FILM COMMISSION

Financing and Accounting Intern

Nairobi, Kenya May 2019 - Aug 2019

- Consolidated and migrated 50K+ financial records from disparate systems into Microsoft Navision ERP system; reduced month-end closing time by 40% and strengthened accuracy of financial reports by 50%
- Posted financial transactions into the financial and vote book systems; consolidated over 30 different financial accounts.
- Prepared 20 payment sources documents (vouchers) daily on average while guaranteeing financial credentials were printed in the correct format.
- Contributed to the department's financial forecasting and risk-analysis; findings that brought the commission a boosted budget of 40% from the Ministry of ICT.

EDUCATION

CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY OF EAST AFRICA

Nairobi, Kenya Aug 2016 - Aug 2021

Bachelor of Commerce Second Class Honours (Lower)

STRATHMORE SCHOOL

Nairobi, Kenya

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (KCSE)

Jan 2012 - Nov 2015

Grade: B+

CERTIFICATES

Certified Mobile Developer

Mar 2016 - Jun 2016

Strathmore University **DELF A2 Certificate**

Jan 2014 - Feb 2014

Alliance Françaises

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Nvumbani Children's Home

Apr 2013 & Aug 2013

Streamlined office administration tasks by creating and implementing a digital filing system and automating manual data-entry tasks; reduced administrative errors by 60% and saved the team 30 hours per week Facilitated daily duties including preparing meals and cleaning the compound over a 7-week period.